JIMMY ALDAPE

Full-Stack Software Engineer

jimmy@jimmyaldape.com https://jimmyaldape.dev https://www.github.com/jimmyaldape

SUMMARY

Experienced and creative software engineer that specializes in the full-stack development, architectural planning of software systems with a focus on web applications

Core competencies include Front-end Development, Back-end Development, Object Oriented Programming (OOP), User Interface Design, Requirement Gathering, Problem Solving and Critical Thinking.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

UC Riverside School of Medicine

2017 - Present Riverside, CA

Led the modernization of all application development writing modern, performant, maintainable code utilizing software engineering principles such as agile software development practices, continuous integration, and test driven development

Developed various school wide web applications leveraging Laravel and Tailwind CCS. AlpineJS, Livewire.

Integrated third party API's into custom applications, alternating between VueJS and ReactJS based on need

Web Developer

Riverside Community College District

2011 - 2017 Riverside, CA

Re-engineered a legacy java based management application using React and .Net Web API that led to an increase in faculty training accountability by 99%

Designed and maintained websites for faculty and using HTML, CSS, and Javascript libraries allowing the faculty to focus on teaching curriculum

Researched trends in current technologies and methodologies of web design that led to an overhaul initiative

Software Engineer Intership

Cal State University, San Bernardino

2014 Riverside, CA

Developed, and implemented a mobile CSUSB Dining Services mobile application for iOS and Android.

Created a custom content management platform to support the CSUSB Dining Services mobile application

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Cal State Univeristy, San Bernardino

2011 - 2016

Software Engineering, Algorithm Analysis, Super Computing and Visualization, Expert Systems, Formal Language and Automata, Computer Architecture, Data Structures, Digital Logic, Machine Organization, File Systems, Operating Systems, Programming Languages, Combinatorics, Discrete Mathematics

SKILLS

Programming Languages

PHP, C#, Javascript

Libraries & Frameworks

Laravel, AlpineJS, Livewire, VueJS, Node, ReactJS, Tailwind CSS, .Net Core

Tools & Platforms

Git, Docker, Webpack, Gulp, Netlify, Composer, Azure

Database

SQL, MySQL, NoSQL, GraphQL

SUCCESSFUL PROJECTS

DOCUVOTER

Web application that streamlined real-time voting on promotions and appointments for faculty and staff and centralized document management into one platform. Led to an increase in productivity by 75% and decreased error rates by 50%.

Built with Laravel, MySQL and Vue.js

https://docuvoter.medsch.ucr.edu

TEACHING TRACKER

Web application that allows teaching activities to be tracked for compensation purposes. Also includes a module for cross marketing by Education Department for available courses.

Built with Tailwind CSS, Alpine-JS, Livewire, and Laravel